# GIOVANNI GARCÍA SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Status: Software and Hardware Developer, Software Engineer

> Skills: C#/.Net, .NetCore, C, C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NodeJs, MS-

SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB

▶ Interests: IoT, Cloud Computing, PaaS, SaaS

▶ Activities: Tennis, Swimming, Video games, Reading, Music

Profile: Experienced software developer passionate for creating cutting-

edge software solutions that boost organizational success's efficacy and efficiency. Possessing a strong command of .NET technologies, I am adept at writing code to build reliable and user-friendly solutions.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/giovannigarcia/



# >>> Experience

# Jan 2021 - Mar 2023 Hardware and Software Engineer - Contractor

Bogotá, COL

## **■** Independent Contractor

Firmware development to OPAL Project IoT Devices.

Technologies: C, FreeRTOS, Typescript, NodeJS, AWS Lambda, IoT.

#### Politécnico Grancolombiano

Design of the structures, forms, and micro-sites of the Digital Campus.

Technologies: Typescript, NodeJS, React, Azure, MongoDB.

#### **■** SmartgridCIS

Providing ongoing Software Engineering, product development and product support services for the Company.

Technologies: C#, .Net, ASP .Net Webforms, React, Azure, MS SQLServer.

## Oct 2017 - Oct 2019 **S**

## **Software Engineer**

Bogotá, COL

#### **■** Sippa Technologies

Software design and development of automatized parking access control, with smart card and ticket printing and LPR integration.

**Technologies:** C#, .Net, WPF, NodeJS, MS SQL Server, MIFARE Cards, IoT, WebAPI, LPR, IoT

#### Feb 2012 - May 2017

#### **Software Development Teacher and Counselor**

Bogotá, COL

- Fundación Universitaria Monserrate
- Institución Universitaria Politécnico Grancolombiano

# 🖪 Institución San Pablo Apóstol, SENA inter-institutional agreement

.NET software development teaching with C# language, driven to ASP .NET MVC webpages and software engineering.

Follow-up of apprentices in the productive stage. Is proposed the design and implementation of an Intership program portal, called CySEP (Control y Seguimiento Etapa Productiva).

**Technologies:** C#, .Net, WinForms, ASP.NET MVC, MS SQL Server, MS Office, Blackboard LMS.

## May 2008 - Dic 2011 Hardware and Software Development Engineer

Bogotá, COL

# Kasei Technologies - Entrepreneurship

Development of a desktop information system for motorcycling competitions designed to facilitate the organization, planning and management of motorcycling competitions.

**Technologies:** C, Microcontrollers, Freescale NXP, RTOS, RS-232, C#, .NetFramework, WinForms, MySQL.

## Feb 2006 - Apr 2008 Hardware Development Engineer - Team Leader

Bogotá, COL

# **Dyetron S.A**

Design and implementation of custom hardware applications, contact with customers and support during project implementation.

**Technologies:** C, Microcontrollers, Freescale NXP, RTOS, MIFARE SmartCards, Zig-Bee. TCP/IP, SPI, I2C, RS-485, RS-232

>>> Education	
2016 - 2017	Advanced Degree (Specialization) in Software Engineering
	<b>Final Project:</b> Enterprise Architecture Design Study Case: Centro de Inversiones Empresariales, Individual Public Transport Business Unit.
1999 - 2010	Bachelor Degree in Electronics Engineering
	<b>血</b> Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas
	<b>Final Project:</b> Timing system for cross-country competitions, developed on a Freescale MC9S12D32 microcontroller.

>>> Courses	
2022	ASP.NET Core Clean Architecture & Domain Driven Design
	<b>①</b> Udemy
	ASP.NET Core Architecture course with Visual Studio 2022 and Entity Framework Core 6.
2020	Soluciones de Inteligencia Artificial con Azure
	<b>血</b> Intelligent Traininig - MinTIC - Microsoft
	Microsoft Fundamentos en Azure.
	Microsoft Introducción a la tecnología de inteligencia artificial
	Microsoft creación de bots inteligentes con Azure Bot Service
	Microsoft construyendo soluciones de Machine Learning con Azure
	Microsoft construyendo soluciones de Inteligencia Artificial con Azure